M. SURESH Manager - Design

PROFILE

Engineering With **14+ Years** of Experience in Public and Private Sector Tender Estimation and providing Technical Assistance to Design & Detailing Direction on Civil & Steel Structural / Static Equipment's / Pressure Vessels / Piping.

Working Knowledge of Recognized Industry Zone: Oil & Gas / Petrochemicals / Refinery / Fertilizer / Power & Chemicals and Industry Codes & Standards: ASCE 7 - 02 & 10 / IS / ANSI / ASME, ASTM / API / BIS / EN / OSID / NFPA

CONTACT

Mobile:

+91-99620 32412

Email: suray088@gmail.com

Address: 23 / 1D, Old Well Street, Thiruvottiyur, Chennai - 600 019

PERSONAL INFO

Date Of Birth: 31-12-1988

Marital Status: Single

Nationality: Indian

Language: Tamil & English

Passport No: V1622244, Valid: 21-07-

2031

HOBBIES

Listening Songs.

Browsing internet to learn new things for developing the Knowledge.

EDUCATION

POLYTHECHNIC: P.T. LEE CHENGALVARAYA NAICKER POLYTECHNIC

COLLEGE, Location: Vepery, Chennai, Tamil Nadu

DIPLOMA: ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING

Year: 2004 - 2008 [Scored - 62%]

SSLC: JAIGOPAL GARODIA GOVERNMENT HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL,

Location: Thiruvottiyur, Chennai, Tamil Nadu

Year: 2004 [Scored - 50%]

WORK EXPERIENCE

ZETWERK MANUFACTUIRNG BUSINESSES PVT. LTD, Location: Bangalore [Manager - Design]

Year: $JULY - 02^{nd} - 2023$ Till Now.

Responsibilities: Estimation Support & Managing Engg. Team.

MAHATHI INFRA SERVICES PVT. LTD, Location: Hyderabad [Manager - Proposal & Design]

Year: March - 05th - 2021 (TO) July - 02nd - 2022 **= 1.4 Yrs** & 01st - Oct - 2022 (TO) April 2023 **= 7 Mnths**

Responsibilities: Estimation / Static & Pressure Vessels - Design & Detailing

Engineering

FENIX TECH ENGINEERING INDIA (OPC) PVT. LTD, Location: Chennai

[Manager - Proposal & Design]

Year: 2019 TO 2021 - 1.2 Yrs.

Responsibilities: Estimation / Static Equipment - Design & Detailing

Engineering / Purchase Assistance to client.

GULF ENGINEERS & CONSTRUCTORS PVT. LTD, Location: Chennai

[Lead Executive - Design]

Year: 2008 TO 2019 - 11.6 Yrs.

Responsibilities: Estimation / Static & Pressure Vessels - Design & Detailing

Engineering

SOFT SKILLS

 ✓ Auto Cad & Auto Plant 3D / Intergraph Tank & PV Elite / SP3D & Navis Work / MS Office

Roles And Responsibilities as Follows:

Estimation:

- ✓ Develop Budgets, Estimate Labor, Material, Construction Costs and Project Schedules & Rate analysis.
- ✓ Develop manpower charts and schedules
- ✓ Support Proposal Reviews with Management.
- ✓ Work With Engineering Team to Get Technical Information to Prepare Offers with Cost Effective Solutions
- ✓ Develop Proposal Complete in All Respects Against the Inquiry Including Technical Compliance
- ✓ Provide Timely Updates on Orders Forecast
- ✓ Work With the Sales Team to Professionally Represent the Company at Customer Meetings
- ✓ Ensuring That the Proposal Is in Conformity with the Specification or Deviation Strategy as Defined by Project Manager.
- ✓ Technical Negotiations with Customer Under the Overall Lead of The Tender Project Manager
- ✓ Support To Management for Analysis of Costs / Budget for Projects.
- ✓ Ensuring That Technical Deviations Provided by Each Partner Are Consistent With Each Other And in Line with The Overall Project Deviation Strategy
- ✓ Implementation Of Procurement Concept Defined by Tender Project Manager in Co-ordination with the Procurement Department.

Civil & Steel Structural Building's:

- ✓ Detailing Engineering of Civil Foundations.
- ✓ Prepare The Detail Engineering with Connection Details and Fabrication Details as Follows: (A) Pre Engineering Building (PEB), (B.) Storage Shed's & (C.) Pipe Rack's and Pipe Bridge Structural Supports (D) Piping Supports
- ✓ Prepare Material List for Estimation & Procurement List for Material Purchase.

Static Equipment / Pressure Vessels / Piping:

- ✓ Pressure Vessels Design and Detailing as Per ASME SEC. VIII DIV.1 & 2 / PD5500.
- ✓ Design & Detail Engineering for Atmospheric Storage Tanks as Per CODE API 650, API 620, API 653 & IS
 803.
- ✓ Design And Detail Engineering of Heat Exchanger, Silo's, Column and Chimneys as Per Relevant Codes and Good Engineering Practice.
- ✓ Petroleum Tanks Fire Water MV Sprinkler System and Foam Water System Design and Detail engineering as per OISD & NFPA Codes.
- Coordinate The Client or Consultant for The Submission and Approval of Revisions for The Plan
 Drawings and Mechanical Design Documents.
- ✓ Review Mechanical Documents for Potential Conflict with Other Disciplines.

Curriculum Vitae

- Review and Approval the Detailed Drawings for Cone Roof Tanks, Dome Roof Tanks & Mild Steel and Aluminum Deck or Hybrid Aluminum External and Internal Floating Roof Vertical Tanks as Per Code (Or) Purchaser Requirements.
- ✓ Plant Modeling Done as Per Purchaser Information Tool used Sp3d.
- Preparation Of P & ID / Plot Plan / Piping Layout / Isometric Drawings for IBR & NON-IBR Lines and Oil & Gas / Power & Process Sectors by Following Relevancy Codes ASME 31.1 Power Piping & ASME 31.3process Piping
- ✓ Lead And Co-Ordination the Team

Current Working Project: -

- ✓ IOCL Panipat Composite Work (Civil, Structural, Mech, Piping, Electrical & Instrument).
- ✓ IOCL Barauni Composite Work (Civil, Structural, Mech, Piping, Electrical & Instrument).
- ✓ NALCO Bauxite Grinding Unit / Evaporation Unit / Calcination Unit

Previous Working Project: -

- More than 80 and above projects worked with Public / Private Sector Project / Oil & Gas Industry / Refinery.
- ✓ Numaligarh Refinery Limited, Assam (Expansion Project for Phase II) EPC Tankage Project.
- ✓ Hindustan Petroleum Corporation Limited, Mangalore Location Caver Storage (-)156Mtr Below Ground.
- ✓ HRRL Rajasthan Refinery Limited Package Civil, Piping Tankage, Electrical & Instrumentation.

Affirmation

I hereby confirm that the information given above is true to the best of my knowledge.

Date: Yours Truly,

Place: Thiruvottiyur, Chennai

(M. Suresh)